Markazi AD.MC.025
Akkasah: Photography Archive (NYU Abu Dhabi)
Markazi
2017
Akkasah: Photography Archive (NYU Abu Dhabi)
AD.MC.025
1 Terabytes
Biographical / Historical
Nadia Benchallal was born in 1963 in Orthez-France to French Algerian parents. In 1991, she studied photography at the International Center of Photography in New York City. She subsequently acquired professional experience assisting photographers such as Joshua Greene, Antoine Verglas, Martine Barrat, Arthur Elgort, and the portraitist Annie Leibovitz. In 1992, Benchallal began a personal project on the everyday life of Algerian women. She then decided to extend her work to a larger theme: Muslim women over the world. It gave her the opportunity to travel widely over the years, exploring her vision of the lives of Muslim women in Algeria, Bosnia, Palestine, Burma, Iran, and Malaysia. Since 1994, she has worked internationally for magazines, such as Le Monde, GEO, La Republica, El PaÏs, L'Orient Express, The New York Times, and Aperture. Her work was exhibited on multiple occasions, most recently 'Sisters' was shown at the University of New York in Abu Dhabi. For three years, Benchallal taught photography at the 'Buc Ressources' school of social workers near Versailles. In 2011, she was invited to be a jury member of The China International Press Photo Contest.
Arrangement
This collection was processed as it was received.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Scope and Contents
Markazi casts light on the conditions of mobility and immobility in Yemen and the Horn of Africa through its focus on household composition and everyday life in the Markazi refugee camp in Obock, Djibouti. Markazi—meaning "central" in Arabic—is a site of convergence for approximately 2,000 persons fleeing the ongoing conflict and humanitarian crisis in Yemen. It is also located at a crossroads, situated within kilometers of the Red Sea harbors from where thousands of young Ethiopian migrants disembark on their own perilous sea crossings to Yemen with the intent of reaching Saudi Arabia to find work. Taken over the course of several extended visits to Obock in 2016–2018, Benchallal's photographs depict these refugees' daily efforts and exertions to survive their encampment on this windswept, desert plain. Text by Nathalie Peutz.
Digital Photographs; Obock, Djibouti; Refugees; International migration; Group Portraits; Individual Portraits
- A refugee from Yemen sitting outside her tent., December 2016; cuid1403 (Object AD_MC_025_ref1_000001_m)
  Refugees; Women; Digital Photographs; Obock, Djibouti; Tents; Individual Portraits
- A Yemeni youth in Northern Djibouti., December 2016; cuid1404 (Object AD_MC_025_ref2_000001_m)
  Obock, Djibouti; Children; Refugees; Boys; Digital Photographs; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Individual Portraits
- To pass time, a refugee catches and releases birds., December 2016; cuid1405 (Object AD_MC_025_ref3_000001_m)
  Obock, Djibouti; Birds; Animals; Children; Refugees; Digital Photographs; Boys; Individual Portraits
- Two children playing volleyball in front of a tent., December 2016; cuid1406 (Object AD_MC_025_ref4_000001_m)
  Sports; Tents; Digital Photographs; Children; Obock, Djibouti; Refugees; Group Portraits; Girls; Boys
- A girl sitting on the roof of a tent., December 2016; cuid1407 (Object AD_MC_025_ref5_000001_m)
  Refugees; Tents; Girls; Children; Digital Photographs; Obock, Djibouti; Individual Portraits
- Two girls sitting in a makeshift swings., December 2016; cuid1408 (Object AD_MC_025_ref6_000001_m)
  Digital Photographs; Obock, Djibouti; Refugees; Girls; Children; Group Portraits; Tents
- Natural landscape in Obock, Djibouti., December 2016; cuid1409 (Object AD_MC_025_ref7_000001_m)
  Obock, Djibouti; Mountains/Hills; Digital Photographs; Landscapes
- A landscape view of the Markazi camp for refugees from Yemen in Obock, Djibouti., December 2016; cuid1411 (Object AD_MC_025_ref9_000001_m)
  Obock, Djibouti; Refugees; Tents; Digital Photographs; Landscapes
- The camp's kindergarten supported by the Japanese NGO, ICAN., December 2016; cuid1412 (Object AD_MC_025_ref10_000001_m)
  Obock, Djibouti; Women; Niqab/Burqa; Boys; Girls; Refugees; Schools/Education; Children; Digital Photographs; Kindergartens/Nurseries
- A tent in front of two UNHCR containers. Graffiti on one of the containers reads: "I feel like the incredible Hulk. My back has been broke but I can still walk."., December 2016-2017; cuid1413 (Object AD_MC_025_ref11_000001_m)
  Tents; Refugees; Digital Photographs; Obock, Djibouti; Graffiti
- Women at a training class., December 2016; cuid1414 (Object AD_MC_025_ref12_000001_m)
  Obock, Djibouti; Niqab/Burqa; Refugees; Digital Photographs; Women; Group Portraits; Head Covers/Veils; Regional/National Dress
- A camp volunteer organizes activities for the children., December 2016; cuid1415 (Object AD_MC_025_ref13_000001_m)
  Head Covers/Veils; Women; Digital Photographs; Refugees; Boys; Obock, Djibouti; Children; Girls; Group Portraits; Head Covers/Veils; Tents
- Pupils going to school., December 2016; cuid1416 (Object AD_MC_025_ref14_000001_m)
  Schools/Education; Obock, Djibouti; Boys; Girls; Refugees; Children; Digital Photographs; Tents
- A boy having his height checked., December 2016; cuid1417 (Object AD_MC_025_ref15_000001_m)
  Digital Photographs; Obock, Djibouti; Refugees; Children; Boys; Men; Regional/National Dress; Group Portraits; Tents
- Inside the camp's hospital., December 2016; cuid1418 (Object AD_MC_025_ref16_000001_m)
  Children; Refugees; Tents; Digital Photographs; Men; Obock, Djibouti; Hospitals; Arabic Writing; Group Portraits
- A woman lying on a Tihama-style bed., December 2016; cuid1419 (Object AD_MC_025_ref17_000001_m)
  Obock, Djibouti; Tents; Women; Digital Photographs; Refugees; Individual Portraits; Furnishings
- Clothes lines between containers and graffiti on a wall., December 2016; cuid1420 (Object AD_MC_025_ref18_000001_m)
  Digital Photographs; Obock, Djibouti; Refugees; English Writing; Tents
- A mosquito-net protects an individual sleeping on a mattress outdoors., December 2016; cuid1421 (Object AD_MC_025_ref19_000001_m)
  Refugees; Digital Photographs; Obock, Djibouti; Furnishings; Buildings
- Two girls in donated Eid dresses., December 2016; cuid1422 (Object AD_MC_025_ref20_000001_m)
  Girls; Children; Digital Photographs; Refugees; Obock, Djibouti; Eid; Group Portraits
- Refugees walking at the side of the road. To reach town, the refugees walk five kilometers or pay for rides on motorized rickshaws., December 2016; cuid1423 (Object AD_MC_025_ref21_000001_m)
  Men; Digital Photographs; Obock, Djibouti; Streets/Roads; Motorcycles; Refugees; Transportation; Mirrors
- An elderly man seated on a plastic chair in a tent., December 2016; cuid1424 (Object AD_MC_025_ref22_000001_m)
  Tents; Refugees; Men; Digital Photographs; Obock, Djibouti; Individual Portraits
- An elderly woman in a tent. Some families have four generations living under one roof., December 2016; cuid1425 (Object AD_MC_025_ref23_000001_m)
  Obock, Djibouti; Tents; Head Covers/Veils; Refugees; Digital Photographs; Women; Individual Portraits
- A girl shows off her henna decorations., December 2016; cuid1426 (Object AD_MC_025_ref24_000001_m)
  Children; Refugees; Digital Photographs; Girls; Obock, Djibouti; Individual Portraits
- A group of refugees selling sweets to make a living., December 2016; cuid1427 (Object AD_MC_025_ref25_000001_m)
  Boys; Girls; Children; Digital Photographs; Refugees; Obock, Djibouti; Food
- A solar-powered fan keeps flies off of a sleeping child's face., December 2016; cuid1428 (Object AD_MC_025_ref26_000001_m)
  Obock, Djibouti; Children; Digital Photographs; Refugees; Individual Portraits; Machines
- A woman standing in the kitchen area of a tent., December 2016; cuid1429 (Object AD_MC_025_ref27_000001_m)
  Refugees; Digital Photographs; Obock, Djibouti; Women; Food; Tents; Individual Portraits; Regional/National Dress
- Kindergarten., December 2016; cuid1430 (Object AD_MC_025_ref28_000001_m)
  Girls; Refugees; Schools/Education; Boys; Digital Photographs; Children; Obock, Djibouti; Kindergartens/Nurseries
- A child poses in his family's home garden., December 2016; cuid1431 (Object AD_MC_025_ref29_000001_m)
  Obock, Djibouti; Individual Portraits; Children; Refugees; Digital Photographs; Individual Portraits
- A girl climbs onto a motorbike outside of the camp's handful of of shops., December 2016; cuid1432 (Object AD_MC_025_ref30_000001_m)
  Girls; Motorcycles; Children; Boys; Digital Photographs; Refugees; Obock, Djibouti; Transportation; Arabic Writing; Group Portraits; Head Covers/Veils; Regional/National Dress
- A woman looking out of the window of her IKEA caravan., December 2016; cuid1434 (Object AD_MC_025_ref32_000001_m)
  Women; Obock, Djibouti; Girls; Digital Photographs; Head Covers/Veils; Refugees; Transportation; Children; Group Portraits
- A child, held by a woman, getting vaccinated., December 2016; cuid1435 (Object AD_MC_025_ref33_000001_m)
  Refugees; Medicine; Women; Children; Obock, Djibouti; Digital Photographs; Group Portraits; Boys; Girls
- Children sitting on the "adults' seats"., December 2016; cuid1436 (Object AD_MC_025_ref34_000001_m)
  Furnishings; Group Portraits; Obock, Djibouti; Children; Girls; Digital Photographs; Refugees; Group Portraits; Transportation
- A man standing in a shop. A sign above him reads: "Ask me to get out of this desert"., December 2016; cuid1437 (Object AD_MC_025_ref35_000001_m)
  Refugees; Men; Shops; Digital Photographs; Obock, Djibouti; English Writing; Arabic Writing; Shops; Individual Portraits
- Mosquito nets and fishing nets enclose an outdoor space., December 2016; cuid1438 (Object AD_MC_025_ref36_000001_m)
  Obock, Djibouti; Tents; Refugees; Digital Photographs
- Two Yemeni women volunteers working in the camp hospital., December 2016; cuid1439 (Object AD_MC_025_ref37_000001_m)
  Obock, Djibouti; Tents; Refugees; Niqab/Burqa; Children; Digital Photographs; Women; Hospitals; Arabic Writing; Head Covers/Veils; Regional/National Dress
- Fishing nets laid out to be disentangled in a fisherman's courtyard., December 2016; cuid1440 (Object AD_MC_025_ref38_000001_m)
  Women; Tents; Refugees; Obock, Djibouti; Digital Photographs
- A person sleeping on a wooden bed inside a tent., December 2016; cuid1441 (Object AD_MC_025_ref39_000001_m)
  Tents; Refugees; Digital Photographs; Obock, Djibouti; Furnishings; Individual Portraits
- A man leans against the exterior of the camp fence while people wait for food distribution inside., December 2016; cuid1442 (Object AD_MC_025_ref40_000001_m)
  Women; Refugees; Obock, Djibouti; Men; Digital Photographs; Head Covers/Veils; Electricity; Facial Hair; Regional/National Dress; Group Portraits
- A Yemeni man uses the inside of his caravan shelters as a canvas on which to depict the conflict he fled., December 2016; cuid1443 (Object AD_MC_025_ref41_000001_m)
  Men; Refugees; Digital Photographs; Obock, Djibouti; Prayer Beads; Art; Individual Portraits
- Women and children sitting outside a container, one woman taking a selfie., December 2016; cuid1444 (Object AD_MC_025_ref42_000001_m)
  Goats; Animals; Women; Children; Digital Photographs; Refugees; Obock, Djibouti; Group Portraits; Head Covers/Veils; Bags/Purses; Girls; Boys
- A child holding a sheet running across the camp., December 2016; cuid1445 (Object AD_MC_025_ref43_000001_m)
  Refugees; Tents; Obock, Djibouti; Children; Digital Photographs; Streets/Roads; Individual Portraits
- A man and two boys with plastic bottles they have collected to recycle., December 2016; cuid1446 (Object AD_MC_025_ref44_000001_m)
  Refugees; Boys; Men; Digital Photographs; Obock, Djibouti; Cars/Trucks; Motorcycles; Transportation; Children; Group Portraits
- A fisherman's daughter returns with their catch., December 2016; cuid1447 (Object AD_MC_025_ref45_000001_m)
  Individual Portraits; Refugees; Girls; Head Covers/Veils; Obock, Djibouti; Digital Photographs; Individual Portraits; Children
- A woman carrying dried wood she has foraged from the surrounding desert., December 2016; cuid1449 (Object AD_MC_025_ref47_000001_m)
  Refugees; Obock, Djibouti; Women; Head Covers/Veils; Digital Photographs; Individual Portraits
- A child looking up at a woman holding a portable MP3 radio., December 2016; cuid1450 (Object AD_MC_025_ref48_000001_m)
  Obock, Djibouti; Children; Refugees; Women; Girls; Digital Photographs; Radios; Group Portraits
- A group of men distributing a charitable donation., December 2016; cuid1451 (Object AD_MC_025_ref49_000001_m)
  Digital Photographs; Obock, Djibouti; Men; Refugees; Group Portraits; Arabic Writing
- Men and their children watch as charitable donations are unloaded, December 2016; cuid1452 (Object AD_MC_025_ref50_000001_m)
  Girls; Refugees; Obock, Djibouti; Children; Boys; Digital Photographs; Men; Head Covers/Veils; Group Portraits
- A man, fatigued, lies down on the playground wall., December 2016; cuid1453 (Object AD_MC_025_ref51_000001_m)
  Men; Obock, Djibouti; Boys; Girls; Refugees; Children; Digital Photographs; Group Portraits
- Yemenis living in Obock await the distribution of food and supplies., December 2016; cuid1454 (Object AD_MC_025_ref52_000001_m)
  Men; Motorcycles; Refugees; Digital Photographs; Women; Obock, Djibouti; Transportation; Group Portraits; Facial Hair; Boys; Girls; Children; Head Covers/Veils
- A child sits on a man's shoulders during a supplies distribution day., December 2016; cuid1455 (Object AD_MC_025_ref53_000001_m)
  Obock, Djibouti; Niqab/Burqa; Refugees; Women; Head Covers/Veils; Men; Girls; Digital Photographs; Children; Group Portraits; Head Covers/Veils; Gatherings
- A man and a girl carry blankets and rice home., December 2016; cuid1456 (Object AD_MC_025_ref54_000001_m)
  Men; Girls; Digital Photographs; Obock, Djibouti; Head Covers/Veils; Refugees; Children; Group Portraits; Food; Head Covers/Veils; Women
- An external view of a tent and a boy standing at the entrance., December 2016-2017; cuid1457 (Object AD_MC_025_ref55_000001_m)
  Tents; Refugees; Digital Photographs; Boys; Obock, Djibouti; Children; Individual Portraits
- A woman and two children gathered at a table, looking at a worksheet about animals., December 2016; cuid1458 (Object AD_MC_025_ref56_000001_m)
  Refugees; Schools/Education; Children; Digital Photographs; Women; Obock, Djibouti; Arabic Writing
- Three girls in their school uniforms walking to school., December 2016; cuid1459 (Object AD_MC_025_ref57_000001_m)
  Refugees; Girls; Obock, Djibouti; Children; Digital Photographs; Tents; Uniforms; Students; Head Covers/Veils; Group Portraits
- A girl holding back mosquito netting reveals her family's home garden., December 2016; cuid1460 (Object AD_MC_025_ref58_000001_m)
  Tents; Children; Refugees; Girls; Digital Photographs; Obock, Djibouti; Individual Portraits
- Inside a home garden. Home garden projects were supported by the Danish Refugee Council., December 2016; cuid1461 (Object AD_MC_025_ref59_000001_m)
  Digital Photographs; Obock, Djibouti; Girls; Children; Refugees; Tents; Individual Portraits; Gardens
- A teacher with a group of girls in a tent., December 2016; cuid1462 (Object AD_MC_025_ref60_000001_m)
  Schools/Education; Children; Tents; Niqab/Burqa; Girls; Digital Photographs; Women; Obock, Djibouti
- A Yemeni teacher instructs her students., December 2016; cuid1463 (Object AD_MC_025_ref61_000001_m)
  Refugees; Tents; Boys; Children; Schools/Education; Girls; Digital Photographs; Women; Obock, Djibouti; Teachers
- A makeshift classroom in the camp., December 2016; cuid1464 (Object AD_MC_025_ref62_000001_m)
  Refugees; Schools/Education; Men; Girls; Boys; Digital Photographs; Children; Obock, Djibouti
- Sisters, and a toy dove., December 2016; cuid1465 (Object AD_MC_025_ref63_000001_m)
  Obock, Djibouti; Refugees; Girls; Children; Digital Photographs; Toys; Group Portraits
- A Yemeni teacher poses with her students in a tented classroom., December 2016; cuid1466 (Object AD_MC_025_ref64_000001_m)
  Obock, Djibouti; Group Portraits; Refugees; Women; Tents; Girls; Boys; Digital Photographs; Children; Schools/Education
- A girl speaking into a megaphone held by a man, with other girls behind her., December 2016; cuid1467 (Object AD_MC_025_ref65_000001_m)
  Digital Photographs; Refugees; Obock, Djibouti; Children; Girls; Men; Tents; Head Covers/Veils; Boys; Group Portraits
- Women and children laughing inside a tent., December 2016; cuid1468 (Object AD_MC_025_ref66_000001_m)
  Refugees; Goats; Animals; Girls; Head Covers/Veils; Obock, Djibouti; Digital Photographs; Women; Children; Group Portraits; Boys; Tents
- The camp's floodlights provide a few hours of lighting each evening., December 2016; cuid1469 (Object AD_MC_025_ref67_000001_m)
  Refugees; Obock, Djibouti; Digital Photographs; Tents; Landscapes
- Ethiopian migrants walking along the shoreline to Obock port from where they hope to find transport to Yemen., December 2016; cuid1470 (Object AD_MC_025_ref68_000001_m)
  Digital Photographs; Obock, Djibouti; Migration; Coast; Landscapes
- Ethiopian migrants en route to Yemen., December 2016; cuid1471 (Object AD_MC_025_ref69_000001_m)
  Streets/Roads; Migration; Obock, Djibouti; Boys; Men; Digital Photographs; Children; Group Portraits
- A solitary Ethiopian migrant en route to Yemen., December 2016; cuid1472 (Object AD_MC_025_ref70_000001_m)
  Obock, Djibouti; Men; Migration; Digital Photographs; Streets/Roads; Palm Trees; Mountains/Hills; Individual Portraits
- Collected fire wood for a family stove., December 2016; cuid1473 (Object AD_MC_025_ref71_000001_m)
  Digital Photographs; Obock, Djibouti; Refugees
- A Somali family living among the refugees from Yemen., December 2016; cuid1474 (Object AD_MC_025_ref72_000001_m)
  Men; Head Covers/Veils; Digital Photographs; Women; Group Portraits; Refugees; Obock, Djibouti
- A family in their Markazi home, seated on a carpet., December 2016; cuid1475 (Object AD_MC_025_ref73_000001_m)
  Obock, Djibouti; Refugees; Tents; Girls; Children; Boys; Men; Women; Digital Photographs; Group Portraits; Toys; Head Covers/Veils; Facial Hair; Carpets/Rugs
- A family including six children in their Markazi home., December 2016; cuid1476 (Object AD_MC_025_ref74_000001_m)
  Tents; Obock, Djibouti; Boys; Girls; Children; Refugees; Men; Women; Digital Photographs; Facial Hair; Group Portraits; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Head Covers/Veils; Carpets/Rugs
- A family including three men and two women in their Markazi home., December 2016; cuid1477 (Object AD_MC_025_ref75_000001_m)
  Obock, Djibouti; Tents; Women; Refugees; Digital Photographs; Men; Group Portraits; Head Covers/Veils; Furnishings; Hats; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Facial Hair; Carpets/Rugs
- Five students who formed a household., December 2016; cuid1478 (Object AD_MC_025_ref76_000001_m)
  Refugees; Men; Students; Digital Photographs; Obock, Djibouti; Hats; Facial Hair; Group Portraits; Tents
- A young family in their Markazi home., December 2016; cuid1479 (Object AD_MC_025_ref77_000001_m)
  Tents; Girls; Refugees; Men; Women; Group Portraits; Digital Photographs; Obock, Djibouti
- A family outside of their home., December 2016; cuid1480 (Object AD_MC_025_ref78_000001_m)
  Girls; Children; Men; Women; Digital Photographs; Obock, Djibouti; Boys; Refugees; Head Covers/Veils; Group Portraits; Facial Hair
- A family in their courtyard, surrounded by tents., December 2016; cuid1481 (Object AD_MC_025_ref79_000001_m)
  Refugees; Boys; Tents; Children; Girls; Men; Women; Digital Photographs; Head Covers/Veils; Group Portraits
- A family including four children in their courtyard., December 2016; cuid1482 (Object AD_MC_025_ref80_000001_m)
  Women; Children; Digital Photographs; Men; Refugees; Obock, Djibouti; Girls; Boys; Group Portraits; Head Covers/Veils
- A family group of six in their courtyard., December 2016; cuid1484 (Object AD_MC_025_ref82_000001_m)
  Digital Photographs; Refugees; Women; Men; Obock, Djibouti; Group Portraits; Head Covers/Veils; Children; Boys; Hats; Clocks/Watches; Facial Hair
- A female-headed household in the camp., December 2016; cuid1485 (Object AD_MC_025_ref83_000001_m)
  Boys; Refugees; Women; Obock, Djibouti; Men; Digital Photographs; Group Portraits; Children; Facial Hair; Head Covers/Veils; Tents
- A family in their Markazi home, sitting on a bed., December 2016; cuid1486 (Object AD_MC_025_ref84_000001_m)
  Children; Boys; Men; Women; Refugees; Digital Photographs; Obock, Djibouti; Girls; Tents; Group Portraits; Head Covers/Veils; Facial Hair; Hats; Tents; Furnishings
- A family in their storefront., December 2016; cuid1487 (Object AD_MC_025_ref85_000001_m)
  Men; Women; Shops; Children; Refugees; Obock, Djibouti; Digital Photographs; Group Portraits; Head Covers/Veils; Facial Hair; Food; Shops; Boys
- A family group of three in their Markazi home., December 2016; cuid1488 (Object AD_MC_025_ref86_000001_m)
  Head Covers/Veils; Obock, Djibouti; Tents; Women; Refugees; Men; Digital Photographs; Group Portraits
- A family in their courtyard, in front of a tent., December 2016; cuid1489 (Object AD_MC_025_ref87_000001_m)
  Refugees; Obock, Djibouti; Women; Children; Digital Photographs; Girls; Boys; Group Portraits; Head Covers/Veils; Tents
- A family including four children in their Markazi home., December 2016; cuid1490 (Object AD_MC_025_ref88_000001_m)
  Children; Boys; Obock, Djibouti; Women; Digital Photographs; Refugees; Girls; Tents; Group Portraits; Head Covers/Veils
- A family including three children in their Markazi home., December 2016; cuid1491 (Object AD_MC_025_ref89_000001_m)
  Children; Tents; Men; Women; Refugees; Obock, Djibouti; Digital Photographs; Group Portraits; Head Covers/Veils
- A man posing in his museum-garden., December 2016; cuid1492 (Object AD_MC_025_ref90_000001_m)
  Refugees; Obock, Djibouti; Digital Photographs; Men; Hats; Individual Portraits; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses
- A family in their Markazi home, in a yellow tent., December 2016; cuid1493 (Object AD_MC_025_ref91_000001_m)
  Tents; Boys; Men; Women; Refugees; Obock, Djibouti; Digital Photographs; Group Portraits; Children; Head Covers/Veils
- A family group of six in their courtyard., December 2016; cuid1494 (Object AD_MC_025_ref92_000001_m)
  Digital Photographs; Obock, Djibouti; Children; Refugees; Women; Men; Group Portraits; Boys; Girls; Head Covers/Veils; Facial Hair
- A family standing in their courtyard., December 2016; cuid1495 (Object AD_MC_025_ref93_000001_m)
  Refugees; Obock, Djibouti; Children; Women; Men; Digital Photographs; Group Portraits; Boys; Girls; Head Covers/Veils; Facial Hair; Tents; Books
- A man and his nephew at their container home., December 2016; cuid1496 (Object AD_MC_025_ref94_000001_m)
  Doors/Entrances; Hats; Refugees; Obock, Djibouti; Men; Digital Photographs; Group Portraits; Facial Hair; Hats
- A family in their home-garden., December 2016; cuid1498 (Object AD_MC_025_ref96_000001_m)
  Women; Obock, Djibouti; Men; Refugees; Children; Digital Photographs; Boys; Girls; Head Covers/Veils; Facial Hair; Gardens; Group Portraits
- A family group of three in their courtyard., December 2016; cuid1500 (Object AD_MC_025_ref98_000001_m)
  Women; Children; Obock, Djibouti; Men; Refugees; Digital Photographs; Group Portraits; Boys; Head Covers/Veils; Facial Hair
- A family group of four in their Markazi home., December 2016; cuid1501 (Object AD_MC_025_ref99_000001_m)
  Obock, Djibouti; Digital Photographs; Children; Women; Niqab/Burqa; Refugees; Men; Group Portraits; Head Covers/Veils; Boys; Facial Hair; Furnishings; Tents; Carpets/Rugs
- A family group of eight in their Markazi home., December 2016; cuid1502 (Object AD_MC_025_ref100_000001_m)
  Obock, Djibouti; Children; Refugees; Women; Head Covers/Veils; Digital Photographs; Group Portraits; Boys; Girls; Tents